

AMIT RUHIL

PROFILE

AR specialist with a warm and friendly demeanor always! Skilled at conflict resolution. My goal is to transit my enthusiasm, creativity & experience into a position. I am certain that my presence in your team will be beneficial to your organization. As such, I would welcome an opportunity to speak with you to evaluate your needs & share my ideas. Track record of being an essential part of the management team and instrumental in providing effective solutions that produce immediate impact and contribute to the establishment's longterm success.

CONTACT

PHONE: 8689099521

EMAIL Amitruhil23396@gmail.com

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

Craft beer

Novels Movies Travel Great food

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Accounts Receivable (AR) Specialist

Wipro Ltd., Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh November, 2021 to June, 2022.

- Working on denials, AR Follow-Up, Appeals, and Websites Logins.
- Working with management, project support and AR specialists as a team to maximize returns for a specified client with revenue cycle optimization.
- Timely management of unpaid claims and ensure secondary claims are submitted and paid.
- Building strategies that minimize errors and produces clean claim submissions.
- Resolving incoming requests from the client and patient financial representatives in a timely fashion.
- Assisting RCM Manager with process improvements to increase revenue and manage time.
- Enforcing managements goals to spot denial trends, documenting them and find an immediate resolution.
- Ensure all workflow items are completed within the set turn-around-time within quality expectations
- Review outstanding insurance balances to identify and resolve issues preventing finalization of claim payment; including coordinating with payers, patients and clients when appropriate.
- Perform other duties as assigned.
- Responsible for accurate and timely daily reports.

Accounts Receivable (AR)

Optum Global Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Gurugram, Haryana May, 2019 to August, 2021

- Research, identify and obtain data/information needed to help process claims orresolve claims issues (e.g., verify pricing, prior authorizations, applicable benefits)
- Posted payments received account discrepancies. Made any necessary adjustments.
- Reviewed weekly aging reports and determined appropriate collection actions.
- Worked with insurance companies to resolve discrepancies with claim medications.
- Provided physician billing, training and collection support to MSO and employed practices.
- Researched, appealed and resolved Medicare, Medicaid and Commercial insurance claims rejections, underpayments and denials.
- Provided support to management by communicating in a timely basis.
- Identify and apply knowledge of new plans/customers to process their claimsappropriately.

- Identify and resolve claims processing errors/issues and trends, as needed (e.g.,related to system configuration, network, eligibility, data accuracy, vendor-related, provider)
- Mentoring new reps & creating their Key Responsibility Areas and following up and also making their productivity as per their performance and at the same time keeping in my mind about client satisfaction and retention.
- Achieve applicable performance metrics (e.g., productivity, quality, TAT).

Accounts Receivable (AR)

Bizztor Media Pvt. Ltd., Gurugram, Haryana June, 2017 to April, 2019

- Understand the client requirements and specifications of the project.
- Call Insurance carrier document the notes in software and spreadsheet and take appropriate action.
- Identify issues and escalate the same to the immediate supervisor
- Ensure that the deliverable to the client adhere to the quality standards.
- o Ensure follow up on pending claims.

EDUCATION

Indra Gandhi National Open University, Rajghat, New Delhi December 2019 M. Com

Shyam Lal College, University of Delhi, New Delhi July 2017 B. Com (Hons)

KEY SKILLS AND CHARACTERSITICS1

- Excellent listener
- o Friendly, courteous, and service oriented
- o Poised under pressure
- Staff Training & Coaching
- Quality Assurance
- Solid written and verbal communicator